<element xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../presentation.xsd">
    <description>
        A component that generates a user interface for editing the properties of a bean. This is the central component of the org.apache.tapestry.corelib.components.BeanEditForm, and utilizes a\
        org.apache.tapestry.corelib.components.PropertyEditor for much of its functionality.
    </description>

    <parameters>
        <parameter name="model">
            The model that identifies the parameters to be edited, their order, and every other aspect. If not specified, a default bean model will be created from the type of the object bound to\
            the object parameter.
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="object">
            The object to be edited by the BeanEditor. This will be read when the component renders and updated when the form for the component is submitted. Typically, the container will listen\
            for a "prepare" event, in order to ensure that a non-null value is ready to be read or updated.
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="overrides">
            Where to search for local overrides of property editing blocks as block parameters. Further, the container of the overrides is used as the source for overridden validation\
            messages. This is normally the component itself, but when the component is used within a BeanEditForm, it will be the BeanEditForm's block parameter that will be searched.
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="remove">
            A comma-separated list of property names to be removed from the org.apache.tapestry.beaneditor.BeanModel. The names are case-insensitive.
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="reorder">
            A comma-separated list of property names indicating the order in which the properties should be presented. The names are case insensitive. Any properties not indicated in the list\
            will be appended to the end of the display order.
        </parameter>
    </parameters>
</element>